# John Cedrick T. Dela Carcel

Marikina, National Capital Region, Philippines



ictdelacarcel@gmail.com





in linkedin.com/in/newbie-cedrick

# Summary

My journey into web development started when I joined Village88, a bootcamp that focusing in full-stack web development. Since then, I've been honing my skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and various web development frameworks and libraries such as Vue.js, Laravel, and Tailwind CSS. In my experiences, I prioritize clean, maintainable code and responsive design that looks great on any device. I love to challenge myself and push my skills to the limit by taking on projects that require me to learn new technologies and techniques.

## **Experience**

### **Junior Developer**

Prescribe Digital || Oct 2022 - Mar 2023 (6 months)

I contributed to backend development and little bit frontend development. The tech stack used are Laravel and Vue JS. Some features that I created in the system:

- created hospital API (CRUD system, frontend UI)
- created other APIs features that are required in the core system
- generating report files in excel format with required data, fields and templates
- integrate a 3<sup>rd</sup> party speech recognition application in .Net CLI application.

# **Full Stack Developer**

XpertU || Aug 2022 - Sep 2022 (1 month)

This is a startup company and the start of my experience in Laravel and Vue coding.

I developed an attendance management system with the use of Laravel API and Vue JS. Some features I created are:

- user login/register with Passport authentication
- real-time notification with the use of Laravel Echo and Pusher JS
- time in time out system (CRUD) and list the history logs of it
- created an admin and user dashboard UI.

### **Web Development Intern**

SMESoft Inc. || Apr 2021 - Jun 2021 (2 months)

Contributed in creating a Water Station Management System, the technologies that we used is ReactJS Framework, PHP, MySQL, and Bootstrap. We give a time to finish it by 3-4 weeks. Our system was 60% functional with CRUD application, login/register, and admin dashboard. I contributed to login/registration (UI and backend), CRUD application and the other simple UI editing.

# **Training**

# **Full Stack Developer Trainee**

Village 88, Inc. - Philippines Jan 2022 - Jun 2022 (5 months)

- It is a 5-month training of full-stack web development will undergo in web fundamentals, advance PHP, advance JavaScript, and back-end development.

#### Education

## **Polytechnic University of the Philippines**

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science July 2018 – September 2022

## **Technological Institute of the Philippines**

High School Diploma, Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics 2016 - 2018

### **Certifications**

- Web Fundamentals Village 88, Inc. Philippines
- Advance Javascript Village 88, Inc. Philippines
- Advance PHP Village 88, Inc. Philippines
- Ruby/Ruby on Rails Village 88, Inc. Philippines
- Zuitt Open House: Free Basic Web Development Crash Course Zuitt Coding Bootcamp

#### **Skills**

- Web Fundamentals: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Frontend: CSS, Tailwind, Node JS, Express JS, JQuey, Vue JS
- Backend: PHP, Ruby, Laravel, Codelgniter, Rails
- Database: MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server
- Tools: Git, Postman, Nginx